# LUIS FLORES

Software Developer & Data Analyst

# **CONTACT**



(669) 333-1236



ricardoluis6212@gmail.com



https://github.com/flores-luis



https://flores-luis.github.io/portfolio/



https://www.linkedin.com/in/flores-luis/

# **SKILLS**

#### **PROGRAMMING**

SQL, Python, Java, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

#### FRAMEWORKS / TOOLS

Bootstrap, Flask, Spring MVC, Tableau, Power BI, GitHub - Git, Terminal

#### DATABASE MANAGEMENT

MySQL, MSSQL, Oracle

# **EDUCATION**

#### SJ CODING DOJO

SOFTWARE DEVELOPEMENT

#### OHLONE COLLEGE

**BUSINESS & DATA ANALYTICS PROGRAM** 

# **PROJECTS**

## **Data Analytics**

- Create Tableau live reports showing data trends
- Python Scripting w/ SQL & Automation

## To Do App - Full Stack Application

- Front End with HTML5/CSS3/JS/Bootstrap
- Server Side with Python-Flask
- DBMS using MySQL
- Cloud Server w/ Amazon AWS & PythonAnywhere

Home Dashboard -- Coming Soon

# **PROFILE**

Hello! My name is Luis, and I am software developer with 8 months of practice in full stack development, and a data analyst during the day with 2+ years of experience. I started in tech 3 years ago and decided to join a coding bootcamp to further my knowledge. Hence, I have chosen to devote myself to a long life of learning in software. I am confident to innovative and develop solutions that are customized to meet a company's organizational needs, and further their success. My job history (from operations, analytics to development) has been diverse and influenced me into becoming a strategic and effective contributor.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - CODING DOJO (Nov 2021 - August 2022)

- Developed front-end/back-end app using HTML/CSS/JS and Python/Java, use of OOP
- Co-worked with Designers/Sr. Engineers to develop applications based on project requirements
- Regularly meet with new students and experienced developers, and implement best coding practices to improve project effectiveness in product development

### PRODUCTION CONTROL ANALYST - TESLA INC (2020 - Present)

- Developed and modified Tableau reports based on business requirements, and actively listened to cross functional departments needs to provide real-time insights
- Identifying areas of improvement to avoid line down situations by investigating data/machine/associate transactions to able to predict future issues such as demand signals
- Actively participating in the creation of process flows with NPI/Process teams to enhance processes both physical and systematic flow

## SUPPLY CHAIN & LOGISTICS SUPERVISOR - TESLA INC (2018 - 2020)

- Actively participating in the creation of process flows with NPI/Process teams to enhance processes both physical and systematic flow at Tesla Livermore/Newark/Oakland/Austin/Berlin
- Worked on various projects and facilitated the physical and systemic transfer of inventory from Oakland to many CA warehouse facilities during Oakland's warehouse closing.
- Facilitated factory gated vehicle to appropriate destinations, escalated and tracked all vehicles
  under 98% quality specs and with constant damage reports until issues resolved, and actively
  achieved quarter end delivery KPIs to meet Tesla's previous quarter target

### OPERATIONS MANAGER - GAATU INC (2014-2018)

- Completed business trips to Taiwan/Mississippi after project finish to setup and launch project in E-Commerce product development enhancing processes
- Interacting with customer/employee to identify process/quality issues and conducted experiments to determine products' ability to function as intended then implement corrective actions
- Wrote and implemented new operating procedures and trained Process Tech/Associates/Machine Operators/Engineers for updated/ new processes, government, and safety requirements
- Analyze key process trends and translate findings into actionable recommendations. Work closely
  with Software and Project Engineering.